A classic underdoll story.
UglyDolls is a animation, music, family film directed by Kelly Asbury.
In the adorably different town of Uglyville, weirdness is celebrated,
strangeness is special and beauty is embraced as more than meets the eye.
After traveling to the other side of a mountain, Moxy and her UglyDoll friends discover Perfection -- a town where
more conventional dolls receive training before entering the real world to find the love of a child.
Moxy (voice), played by Kelly Clarkson.
Mandy (voice), played by Janelle Monáe.
Ox (voice), played by Blake Shelton.
Wage (voice), played by Wanda Sykes.
Babo (voice), played by Gabriel Iglesias.
Lucky Bat (voice), played by Leehom Wang.
UglyDolls is a 2019 animated musical adventure-comedy film directed by Kelly Asbury and
written by Alison Peck, from a story by Robert Rodriguez, who also produced.
It is based on the plush toys of the same name by David Horvath and Sun-Min Kim, and follows a
group of them as they try to find owners in the "Big World" despite their flaws.
The film stars the voices of Kelly Clarkson, Janelle Monáe, Blake Shelton, Wanda
Sykes, Gabriel Iglesias, Wang Leehom, Nick Jonas, and Pitbull.
UglyDolls was theatrically released by STX Films, the
first animated film produced by the company.
It received negative reviews from critics and grossed $32 million worldwide, and was the
last film directed by Kelly Asbury, who died in June 2020 from cancer.
The film explores themes of musical, based on toy, self image, imperfection.
The tone is lighthearted.